<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lapolis&#39; Notes</title>
    <link>https://lapolis.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Lapolis&#39; Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 08:32:45 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lapolis.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>HacktoberCTF_(palinka_team)</title>
      <link>https://lapolis.github.io/posts/2020/10/hacktoberctf_palinka_team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 08:32:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lapolis.github.io/posts/2020/10/hacktoberctf_palinka_team/</guid>
      <description>Not long ago, during a regular afternoon, I thought to myself: &amp;ldquo;I feel like I want to suffer a bit&amp;rdquo;. I quickly checked what CTF Time had on offer and there it was, the answer to all my dreams: Hacktober CTF.
It was at this point, without pressuring of course&amp;hellip; :P , I check to see if anyone wanted to join me in this, probably painful, adventure.
Still, no pressure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPU_rig_setup_n_maintenance</title>
      <link>https://lapolis.github.io/posts/2020/09/gpu_rig_setup_n_maintenance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 08:38:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lapolis.github.io/posts/2020/09/gpu_rig_setup_n_maintenance/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago, a poor GPU rig, aka Ring0 (long story, don&amp;rsquo;t ask), was full of sticky dust and (probably) dry thermal paste, so I decided that something had to be done; at the end of the day, Ring0 never did anything wrong to deserve that. Keeping in mind my decision, I started to tear down Ring0 aiming for a deep cleaning; fortunately Dennis was there to help making the whole process way quicker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCP_survival_101</title>
      <link>https://lapolis.github.io/posts/2020/09/oscp_survival_101/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 08:59:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lapolis.github.io/posts/2020/09/oscp_survival_101/</guid>
      <description>With this short post I want to put together a few very good tips I found on the internet about how to prepare for and how to survive the OSCP exam. This is not a tool-kit since you will just need a basic Kali installation for your OSCP exam.
 Preparing for the exam Since the OSCP certification is relatively expensive, especially if you&amp;rsquo;re still a student. However, there are simple ways to start preparing even before enrolling in order to save at least a month of paid lab.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
